## **Career Summary:**

4.5 years experienced Java Developer highly skilled in documentation and testing across the complete development life cycle of a product to ensure smooth development. Adapt at identifying bugs and prescribing solutions to increase efficiency of a product. Highly skilled in planning and writing business Logics applications using Java Programming (Java & Spring Boot) and MySQL database and debugging to give best standard support for clients, also have experience in handling a team.

# **Professional Experience:**

## HCL technologies, Bangalore

December 2021 - Till date

- Fixing defects communicated by the users and resolving Jira tickets for L1, L2, L3 levels
- Checking the log, Debug the exception in Eclipse IDE.
- Work on bug fix, code fix and testing in UAT environment
- Testing Web services using postman, Soap UI
- Excellent analytical and problem-solving skills.

# Calpion software technologies, Bangalore

May 2019 – November 2021

- Installing MySQL Database and creating database schema
- Developing view using JSP & JSTL tags
- Developing controllers in java to interact with view and backend business logic
- Developing entity classes
- Fixing defects communicated by the testers
- Developing repositories to perform database operations in Spring boot
- Implementing WebServices using restful
- Developing application based on micro services concept
- Performing form validations using regular expressions
- Testing WebServices using postman
- Generating pdf document using API
- Integrating email sending services
- Configuring application. properties file

### **Skill Sets**

- Languages Java, JavaScript, Spring MVC, Spring Boot with data JPA, Linux
- Database- MySQL
- Tools- Eclipse (Java), STS (Spring Boot), Dbeaver, Post Man, Putty.
- Other Skills: JSP, Java/J2EE, Tomcat V9.0, Servlets, JDBC, Linux, Git/GitHub

## **Project Experience:**

## Project # 1:

• Client : Groupecat

Duration : November 2021 till dateOrganization : HCL Technologies

Project : Support

• Role : Senior software Engineer

### Project Details: vehicle Transport Management System

Automate processes to plan, procure, execute, track and audit transportation for every shipment. Manage hub-to-hub, hub-to-store, and last mile deliveries all on one platform. Assign, track & manage deliveries across own fleet, market vehicles.

Track progress and manage exceptions in-transit. Collect & confirm delivery success. Track live location and status through SIM, GPS or App-based tracking. Enable dealers & distributors to track all shipments sent to their hub on the merchant portal. Give customers an Uber-like delivery experience with map based location tracking & ETAs. Notify customers at every stage of delivery through E-mail, mobile app.

### Project # 2:

• Client : Marktech 3.5

Duration : May 2019 – November 2021
 Organization : Calpion software technologies

Project : SupportRole : Quality Control

#### **Project Details:**

Marktech system gives everyone — from sales, customer service, business development, recruiting, marketing, or any other line of business — a better way to manage the external interactions and relationships that drive success. A Marktech lets you store customer and prospect contact information, identify sales opportunities, record service issues, and manage marketing campaigns, all in one central location — and make information about every customer interaction available to anyone at your company who might need it.

With visibility and easy access to data, it's easier to collaborate and increase productivity. Everyone in your company can see how customers have been communicated with, what they've bought, when they last purchased, what they paid, and so much more. Marktech can help companies of all sizes drive business growth, and it can be especially beneficial to a small business, where teams often need to find ways to do more with less.

## **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION:**

- Bachelor of engineering K.S. Institute of technology, Bangalore Graduated with 66% aggregate
- Diploma in mechatronics engineering S.J (govt). Polytechnic, Bangalore
  I have successfully completed my diploma with 77% aggregate

• SSLC - Jnana sagar English school, Bangalore I have completed my SSLC with 82% aggregate

# PERSONAL DETAILS

- Father Name Ganoji Rao M
- Date of Birth 15-August-1995
- Nationality Indian
- Marital status Single

## **Declaration**

I hereby declare that the above-furnished details are true to the best of my knowledge.

**PLACE: Bangalore** 

Signature: Akash G